(647) 865-3991 Oshawa, Ontario hello@devyratnasari.com

Devy Ratnasari

linkedin.com/in/devy-ratnasari github.com/devyratnasari OCT devyratnasari.com

Data Scientist / Data Analyst / Software Developer

Skilled and results-oriented professional with two years experience in software development with a focus on designing and building an end-user application. Successfully improve the efficiency of the business process. Independently managed, designed and implemented business processes for the company. Awarded recognition for excellent company performance. Viewed as a strong problem solver in intense and demanding environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Python, C#, Java, FlaskAPI, SQL, Mysql, SQLAlchemy

Artificial Intelligence Machine Learning, Deep Learning, OpenCV, TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn

Visualisation Tools Tableau, PowerBI

Cloud AWS EC2, Azure (Fundamentals), Heroku

Application Visual Studio, Jupyter Notebook

PROJECTS

Canada Government Proactive Disclosure Travel Expenses

August 2023 — August 2023

- Developed interactive Tableau visualizations to provide insights from the Canadian government's Proactive Disclosure of travel expenses, contributing to enhanced transparency and accountability.
- Extracted, cleaned, and transformed raw travel expense data for accurate and meaningful representation in Tableau.
- Implemented filters, parameters, and calculated fields in Tableau to enable users to customize their data exploration experience.
- Details: https://devyratnasari.com/visual/can-gov-travel.html

Human Resources Executive Dashboard

August 2023 — August 2023

- Designed and developed a comprehensive Human Resources Executive Dashboard to track key performance indicators (KPIs) and workforce trends.
- Created interactive visualizations using tools like Tableau, enabling executives to monitor recruitment, employee engagement, and retention metrics.
- Implemented dynamic filters and slicers to allow users to explore data by department, tenure, and other relevant dimensions.
- Details: https://devyratnasari.com/visual/HRA-exec-dash.html

Government Bonds Order Prediction

October 2022 — November 2022

- Understanding business requirements and designing ETL processes to transform data from source systems to target systems.
- Ensured data quality and integrity by performing data validation and cleansing activities.
- Analysed Customer behaviour and developed a prediction model using Machine Learning to predict the likeliness of the user ordering bonds.
- Analysis: https://devyratnasari.com/ml/bonds.html

Automatic Attendance Using Face Recognition and Object Detection (Capstone Project)

May 2022 — August 2022

- Constructed a web application for collecting students' attendance using facial recognition. This application could simplify the lecturer's task in taking attendance and calling out each student's name and reduce the possibility of other people taking attendance on behalf of someone else.
- Project: https://devyratnasari.com/cv/attendance.html

Credit Card Detection (Capstone Project)

January 2022 — April 2022

- Mapped and transformed data to a consistent uniform format.
- Validate data to ensure that data is accurate, reliable, and meets the required standards.
- Built a credit card fraud detection model using multiple Machine Learning and Deep Learning algorithms.
- IEEE presentation: Youtube presentation link | Analysis: https://devyratnasari.com/ml/capstone1.html

EDUCATION

Artificial Intelligence Analysis, Design & Implementation - Graduate Certificate Durham College

January 2022 — October 2022

Ontario, Canada

• Conduct research, data analysis, model development, and solution deployment in an ethical manner that protects privacy, and confidentiality, addresses data bias and transparency and ensures data integrity.

Computer Science - Bachelor Degree

BINUS University

September 2009 — April 2013 Jakarta, Indonesia

- Recognizes the new technology trends as the enablers of modern-day business analytics and intelligence for decision support
- · Analyze how organizations employed business analytics and intelligence to make decisions or gain a competitive edge
- Identify Decision Support Opportunities that are supported by business analytics and intelligence.

(647) 865-3991 Oshawa, Ontario hello@devyratnasari.com

Devy Ratnasari

linkedin.com/in/devy-ratnasari github.com/devyratnasari Data Scientist / Data Analyst / Software Developer devyratnasari.com

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

IT Programmer

Agung Sedayu Group

August 2014 — July 2016

Jakarta, Indonesia

- · Collaborate with other team members, such as software engineers, project managers, and legal team members, to understand and translate software requirements into functional code.
- · Write, modify, and debug software programs according to established coding standards. Perform unit testing to ensure the functionality and reliability of the software. Identify and fix defects or bugs that may arise during the testing phase.
- · Investigate and resolve software defects or customer-reported issues. Maintain and update existing software applications to ensure they remain compatible with new operating systems, platforms, or technology upgrades.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Restaurant Manager

Kuon Group

June 2020 — November 2021

Sydney, Australia

- · Leverage the usage of social media during the pandemic for restaurant marketing, resulting in 100% occupancy which led to maximizing the restaurant's sales.
- Designed a customer dictionary system that helps the chefs to know and understand the customer's behaviour. Leading to a better experience for the customer which increased the restaurant's sales.
- Trained 6 staff and managed the restaurants that earned an award from the Australian Good Food Guide for excellent food and service.

Human Resources Assistant

Alila Hotels Jakarta

March 2013 — March 2014

Jakarta, Indonesia

- · Handled medical and other staff benefits.
- Conducted training for new staff and explain their benefits.
- Administered general affairs and liaising between employee union and management if necessary.